《越狱》前情提要K
Previously on Prison Break:
打扰，女士们，我有问题想要请教
Excuse me, ladies. I need to ask you a few questions.
那个恶心的南方人从后门溜出去了
And that dirty southerner, he snuck out the back.
你真的认为钱被恋童癖独吞了？
Do you really think the Diaper sniper got all of it?
如果你是包威 手上拿到五百万美金
If you were Bagwell and you just got your hands on $5 million...
你会去哪里？
...where would you go?
我在城里，彩虹厅里面
I'm right in the city. In the Rainbow Room.
那是纽约市的餐厅
Restaurant in New York City.
我会在那个地点等待
I am gonna be waiting in that spot.
全世界我只希望K
And that's all that I want in this whole world,,,
我的两个女孩在那里等着我
...is for my two girls to be waiting there for me.
三个点K第三个字母
Three dots, third letter.
集合
Rendezvous.
重点是在哪里？
The question is, where?
日落K热
Sundown, hot.
你想告诉我什么？麦可
What? What are you trying to tell me, Michael?
我欠你一个道歉，因为我对你撒谎
I think I owe you an apology because I lied to you...
关于奥斯卡席尔斯的事
...about oscar shales.
在这里
Right there.
我开枪射中他的这里
That's where I put the bullet in him.
你要做什么？
What are you doing, man?
我们聘请你做好工作 原因就不关你的事了
You've been hired to do a job. The reasoning does not concern you.
你不质疑我们
Don't ask any questions about us...
我们也会继续 让他人不质疑你
...we'll continue to make sure no one asks any about you.
清楚了吗？
Are we clear?
他们都得死
They all die.
（布兰丁植物园）
（夜间经理：吉米马登）
-你好 -你好
- Hey. - Hey.
你是新来的？
Are you new?
对
Yeah.
没人跟我说有新的义工来帮忙
No one told me we were getting a new volunteer.
我之前都做夜班打扫的工作
I've been working, the night shifts. Clean up.
吉米答应让我换工作时段K
And Jimmy said I could change my shift, so...
你知道要做什么吧？
You know what you're doing?
知道
Yeah.
-回头见 -好
- I'll see you around. - Right.
（阿帕契沙漠幽灵）
-史柯菲可能出现了 -收到
- This might be scofield. - Copy that,
你从那边过去
You take that side.
-不准动 -别激动
- Freeze! - Take it easy, man.
-不要站起来 -怎么回事？
- Stay on the ground. - What's the deal?
他不见了
He's gone.
-你还好吗？ -还好吧，我想
- How you feeling? - Okay, I guess.
有点累
Tired.
我是逮捕的目标，孩子
I'm a target, kid.
只要跟我在一起 你也变成目标
As long as you're with me, so are you.
要经历千辛万苦 情况才会好转，你懂吗？
Things will get a whole lot worse before they get better. Understand?
可是和麦可叔叔会合后 可以去巴拿马K
After we meet up with Uncle Mike and get to Panama.
巴拿马的事不能保证
Panama ain't a sure thing.
你叔叔的计划很危险 真的太危险了
Your uncle's plan is dangerous. I mean, really dangerous.
听着，对你的所有控诉都被撤销了
Listen, all the charges against you have been dropped.
你没有前科，可以展开新生活 开始更好的人生
You're free and clear to start a new life. A good life.
不用一直提心吊胆的过日子K
Not be running, looking over your shoulder...
你要我离开你？
You want me to leave?
不是
No.
-不是 -很好，因为我不打算走
- No. - Good, because I'm not.
拿去吧
Here you go.
电视音量开大一点，珍妮
Turn the sound up on the tube, Jenny.
好，汉克
Sure, Hank.
对大卫阿普斯基之死 你有何感想？
Do you have any thoughts on the death of David Apolskis?
-这是不幸的事件 -验尸指出他遭到近距离射杀K
- It was unfortunate, - Tests show he was shot at close range,
-大卫 -你是否曾有机会制服他？
- David. - Was there ever any opportunity...?
让我提醒各位，虽然他很年经 大卫阿普斯基K
Let me remind you that despite his age, David "Tweener" Apolskis was...
是名逃犯 他试图抢夺我的枪
...a fugitive who made a move for my weapon.
杀他并非我的本意
I did not want to have to kill him.
但是有些事是你无法掌控的
Sometimes things happen that are just out of your control.
这家伙会把全部人都宰了
That good old boy's hunting them all down, ain't he?
有消息指出 你找到史柯菲的硬碟
Sources claim that you have recovered Scofield's hard drive,
-并且救回其中的大量资讯 -哪来的消息？
- Obtained substantial data from it, - What sources?
据说你不只已取得 史柯菲越狱的方式
Retrieved information detailing not only how Scofield broke out,,,
-还有逃亡计划，对此有话要说吗？ -没有
...but how he plans to stay out. Comment? - No.
今天稍早在布兰丁植物园 发生的事件
The event at Blanding Botanical Gardens earlier today,,,
都要归功于 你从硬碟里取得的资料
...that was a result of hard drive data you collected.
我无可奉告
No comment.
你有发现 他可能去的其他地点吗？
Have you found other locations where Scofield might be?
-我已经说过无可奉告 -这家伙不简单
- I believe I said no comment, - There's something about this guy,
他似乎看透我的想法 知道我们要去哪
It's like he knows where we're going, what we're thinking,
-请透露接下来你要去哪里 -硬碟的功用是什么？
- Tell us where you're heading, - What role will the hard drive play?
这次的侦办细节都是高度机密K
Details of this investigation are extremely confidential,
听说检验结果出炉了，有何发现？
Heard it came back from the lab. Any findings?
有，3200安士的硝酸甘油
Yeah, 3200 nitroglycerine ampoules.
史柯菲知道 必须储藏在阴凉、潮湿之处
Scofield knew these needed to be stored in a cool, moist area.
在犹他沙漠中的 植物园最适合不过了
Best place for that in the Utah desert is the botanical gardens.
-稳定吗？ -都是医疗等级
- Stable? - All medical grade.
平常安全使用在心脏病患上
Safely used by heart patients all the time.
可是全加起来K
But in the aggregate...
那一箱可以把整栋大楼炸掉
It can take out an entire building. That box right there.
所以我们不能有消息K
This is why we can't have leaks...
从办公室走漏出去
...coming from this office.
那些背着我去找媒体的人
God help the agent who goes behind my back...
全都给我小心一点
...and talks to the press.
你能透露这次逮捕行动的方向吗？
Can you elaborate on any of your tactics in this manhunt?
孙子说过 知己知彼K
Sun Tzu said that if you know your enemy,,,
百战百胜
,,, you need not fear 100 battles,
我了解这些人 他们的个性、背景
I know these men, who they are, where they came from,
还有他们的目标
Where they want to go,
（犹他州，莫柏）
这些逃犯要面对无止尽的战争
These convicts are in a constant battle,
（亚历山大曼宏）
敌人不只是我
Not only with me,,,
还有他们自己
,,, but with themselves,
每次做决定前，他们都会迟疑
Second-guessing every decision they make,
（席尔斯登上调查局通缉名单）
我该向左？
Do I turn left?
还是向右？
Do I turn right?
留下或继续走？
Stay or go?
我的职责就在于 查出他们的选择
My job is to know how they'll answer these questions,
（潘蜜拉曼宏 西侧大道90号，已离婚）
要赢得战争，就要透彻了解对方
The only way to win a war is to try to know your prey completely,
接着就能准备齐全 迎战敌军
And then you get to go after your enemy with everything you've got,
片名：越狱风云
剧名：秘密出土
（美国之路廉价商店）
我们半价的东西都在后面
our half price stuff's in the back.
-我要找一个特别的东西 -好
- I'm looking for something very specific. - Okay.
就是这个
This is it.
-我就是需要这个 -太好了
- This is exactly what I need. - Great.
我们今天就差这么一点 就这么一点点
We were just inches away today. Inches.
把这资料放大
I want these blown up huge.
-贴在我的办公室墙壁上 -这是什么？
- Put them up in my office, on the walls. - What are these?
里面有资讯 是关于史柯菲准备的集合地点
In there is information regarding a rendezvous that scofield set up.
我们今天就要破解密码 蓝恩
We're gonna crack that code today. Lang!
富兰克林告诉老婆 今天要在彩虹厅见面
Today's the day Franklin told his wife he'll meet her at the Rainbow Room.
-没错 -错了，今天是富兰克林被逮捕的日子
- Right. - Wrong. Today Franklin's going down.
-准备好了吗？ -一切已经准备就绪
- Are you ready? - Everything's arranged.
（伊利诺州，芝加哥）
-都在这里了吗？ -对
- It's all here? - Yeah.
雷，我们走
Yo, Ray, let's go.
崔，你好吗？
Hey, yo, Trey. What's up, nigga?
-我就知道不是你 -我可不是鬼
- I know that ain't you. - It ain't a ghost, man.
你还好吗？
You holding up all right?
我搭了很久的公车 才抵达芝加哥
Just catching a whole bunch of buses just to get here to Chi-Town, man.
你觉得我的感觉会好吗？
How you think I'm supposed to feel?
克里斯、杰，你们好吗？
Chris, Jay. What's up, Flam?
你看起来瘦了，老哥
You look like you lost a few, bro.
-我吃减肥餐 -是这样吗？
- Slim-Fast, baby. - Is that what it is?
调查局一直盯着你的老婆 到你家监视
Feds been in your old lady's business, no joke. Up in your crib.
-还会跟踪她 -我知道
- Following her around. - Yeah, I know, man.
我知道你爱凯西
Yo, I know you love Kacee.
可是你来这里 我不知道是不是好主意
I don't know if it's a good idea for you to come around here.
你是通缉犯
You're a wanted man.
我被通缉是因为我守口如瓶
I'm wanted because I kept my mouth shut.
让你们不必坐牢
And I kept you out of Fox River.
百元钞票 我们了解，我们欠你人情
C-Man, we feel that. And we owe you one.
很好 我现在要你们还我人情债
Good, because I'm collecting right now.
我妻子今天在等我
My wife is waiting for me...
今天我一定要带家人离开芝加哥 懂了吗？
...and I am not leaving Chi-town without my family, you understand?
你们全都得帮我 我们走吧！
Now, you all are gonna help me. Let's roll out.
你要上哪去？
Where you going?
载女儿去上学
To take my kid to school.
我知道彩虹厅的事
I know about the Rainbow Room.
-我不懂你的意思 -我们窃听你的电话
- I don't know what you're talking about. - Phone lines are tapped.
我们听到你和丈夫的 完整对话内容
We heard your entire conversation with your husband.
既然你和蒂蒂 没有买去纽约的机票
Since you and Dede aren't booked on any flights to New York...
别说彩虹厅是曼哈顿的餐厅
...don't tell me the Rainbow Room is a restaurant in Manhattan.
你可以告诉我 和丈夫的见面地点
Tell me where you're meeting your husband.
不然我可以 在你女儿面前逮捕你
Or I can arrest you. Right in front of your daughter.
你去死吧，我没有做错事
You go to hell. I haven't done anything wrong.
你和一名逃犯谈到 今天要和他见面
You spoke with an escaped felon about meeting him today.
这足够控告你教唆犯罪
You've done enough to be charged with attempt to aid and abet.
拜托，听我说
Please, okay. Listen to me.
我打一通电话 儿童福利局就会来
One phone call and Child Welfare is here.
你去坐牢 蒂蒂会被送去寄养家庭
You're going to County, Dede will be in foster care.
-不 -别担心
- No. - Don't worry.
我听说寄养家庭都是好人家
I hear the families in the foster system are topnotch.
你在要求我 从女儿和丈夫中选择其一
You are asking me to choose between my daughter and my husband.
就是这样
Exactly.
-有消息吗？ -我打去福克斯河监狱
- Anything? - I'm on the phone with Fox River...
问茶包的资料
...checking T-Bag's file.
找到什么资料？
Hey, what you got for me?
真的？52次？哪里？
Really, 52 times? Where?
我欠你一次人情，帕特森
I owe you, Patterson.
我们有很长一段路要赶
We got a lot of road to cover.
（忙蜂餐厅）
（亚利桑那州，圣大卫）
没问题
We're good.
现在我们直接到新墨西哥州
No more stops until we get to New Mexico.
-你忘记拿零钱了 -好
- You forgot your change. - Yeah.
-谢谢 -你一下子就跑掉了
- Thanks. - You were in such a rush.
谢谢K
Thanks. Thank you.
继续走K
Keep walking. Keep walking.
快，继续走
Come on, keep walking.
该死
Damn it.
我们不必丢下车，可以继续开吧
We don't have to ditch the car. We can keep driving.
不行，女侍看见我和车 车子没用了
We can't, the waitress made me and the car. It's useless.
抱歉，也许可以再找一台车
I'm sorry, you know. Maybe we can find another car.
车子不会凭白从树上长出来
Cars aren't exactly growing on trees out here.
还有四百里的路要赶 会赶不到的
We've got 400 miles to go, and no way of getting there.
如果来不及和麦可见面 他会丢下我们
If we don't get to Michael in time, he'll leave without us.
-麦可叔叔才不会这样 -他别无选择
- He wouldn't do that. - He doesn't have a choice.
逃出国外只有一次机会
It's a one-shot deal out of the country.
我已经说抱歉了
I said I was sorry.
-我刚刚看到火车站的路标 -没那么简单
- There was a sign for a train station. - It ain't that easy.
-可以沿着路走，不会被发现的 -没那么简单
- We follow the road, we won't be seen. - It ain't that easy.
我又不是傻瓜 我也曾经逃亡过
Hey, I'm not an idiot. I was on the run too, you know.
对，你逃亡过，可是你被逮到了
Yeah, you were on the run, and you got caught.
我很抱歉，爸 我不是你这种专业犯人
Yeah, well, I'm sorry I'm not a pro at being a con like you, Dad.
当初你要我离开时 我也许就该滚蛋了
Maybe I should've just left when you gave me the out.
反正你也不在乎
Not like you care.
不要激动
Take it easy.
我很抱歉，好吗？
I'm sorry, all right?
对不起，我K
I'm sorry, man, I'm just...
我们快走吧
Let's get out of here.
（科罗拉多州，杜兰戈）
-潘蜜拉曼宏太太？ -是
- Mrs. Pamela Mahone? - Yes.
我是调查局的伟恩梅瑞克探员
Agent Wayne Merrick, FBI.
我想和你谈谈你丈夫的事
I'd like to talk to you about your husband.
我很讶异你会找上我 调查亚历的背景
I'm surprised that you're coming to me for a background check on Alex.
这是标准程序
It's standard procedure.
当探员即将晋升更高阶层时
We run these kind of checks when an agent's about to be promoted...
我们都会做身家调查
...to a higher security clearance.
我知道，他上次升官时 我也经历过了
I know that, I did this dance the last time he was promoted.
我只是想既然我们离婚了K
I just figured that since we were divorced...
我几乎鲜少和他连络 更不会清楚他的职场表现K
I mean, I rarely speak to him, and I certainly don't follow his career...
我今天一定得把事办好
We really need to get this done today.
我保证不会占用你太多时间
So, I promise I won't take up much of your time.
我给前夫的时间已经够了 梅瑞克先生
I've given enough time to my ex-husband, Mr. Merrick.
我懂了
I see.
调查局工作会破坏家庭和谐
The Bureau can take its toll on your family.
我能了解
I understand that.
我的前妻也是探员
My ex-wife is, an agent...
所以我能感同身受
...and let's just say I know how you feel.
可以答应我 谈过的事不让他知道吗？
Promise me that he won't find out we spoke?
这些都是机密
Oh, it's totally confidential.
-介意我问原因吗？ -老实说，他让我害怕
- Do you mind if I ask why? - To be perfectly honest, he scares me.
（伊利诺州，艾尔金）
（有个计划可导正一切）
（凯莉福斯特，伊州艾佛顿市 枫叶街12438号）
查号台
Information,
你好，我要找日落旅馆的电话
Hi, I need the number for a sundown Hotel please.
-哪一州？ -所有州
- What state? - All of them, please.
-南达科他州皮尔有一家 -好
- Got one in Pierre, South Dakota, - okay.
-还有西维吉尼亚的萨顿 -一家在新墨西哥的希拉
Another in Sutton, West virginia, And one in Gila, New Mexico,
（堪萨斯州，垂比云）
-需要效劳吗？ -请给我一把向日葵
- What can I do you for? - A batch of them sunflowers, please.
你别介意，但我觉得
If you don't mind me saying...
你的口音不像堪萨斯人
...you do not sound like you hail from Kansas.
你的耳朵真灵光
You got a sharp ear.
我来自金色啄木鸟州
I hail from what we call the Yellowhammer state.
怎么会来垂比云？
What brings you to Tribune?
（苏珊贺兰德 米贝瑞山庄1605号）
先生？
Sir?
是为了爱情
Romance.
非常感谢你
Thank you so much.
会有人受伤的
Somebody's gonna get hurt,
调查局一定会有备而来
Feds gonna be swinging bigger bats than these.
-我们一定得带武器 -听着，我们只需要K
- We gotta have ours. - Look, man, that's all we need.
你的车 你的卡车和胆量就够了
Is your car, your truck, and some guts, man.
我们不需要带这些枪
We don't need all of this.
-我们应该考虑一下 -我说不行
- Maybe we should think about it. - I said no.
枪林弹雨时会发生什么事？
What's gonna happen, man, when the bullets start flying?
你能保证我和家人不会出事吗？
Can you guarantee my family ain't gonna get hurt?
警察会全副武装，我要严阵以待
Johnny Law's gonna be strapped up. I'm going in hot.
-你似乎没听清楚 -不，是你没听清楚
- I don't think you heard me. - No, I don't think you heard me.
我不要手无寸铁
I'm not going in naked.
我们说好要帮你这个忙
I know we said we'd ride with you on this...
但是我不能不带枪去
...but I'm not going in there without some of these.
你想临阵脱逃吗？
You wanna punk out, man?
那就走吧 我自己可以办得好
Then punk out, because I can do this myself.
没有人要临阵脱逃，我们不带枪
Ain't nobody punking out. And no guns.
但是你最好是对的 因为要是开始枪林弹雨
But you better be right about this, if bullets do start flying...
死的人就是我们
...the only blood being spilt is gonna be ours.
你懂了吗？
You feel me?
懂了
I feel you.
凯勒曼探员K
Agent Kellerman!
-凯勒曼探员 -什么事？
- Agent Kellerman! - Yes?
你要我追踪的名字，凯莉福斯特
That name you wanted me to track. Kelli Foster.
她买了到新墨西哥的机票，刚着陆
She booked a flight to New Mexico. Just landed.
-有人盯着她吗？ -没有，但已查出她租车的车牌
- Got someone on her? - No, but we got an ID on her rental car.
-要我通知金先生吗？ -不用，我自己处理这件事
- Should I update Mr. Kim? - No, I'll take care of this myself.
有女侍说疑似看见柏劳父子
We got a tip from a waitress who thinks she saw Burrows and his son.
-在亚利桑那州圣大卫 -派公路小队去确认
- Outside st. David, Arizona. - Get a road team out there to confirm.
一旦确认是柏劳，立刻通知我
Once they get a beat on Burrows, notify me immediately.
全部出去，动作快
Everybody out. Let's go, come on.
请说
Yeah?
莎拉丹奎迪买了 横越美国的单程机票
Sara Tancredi just booked a one-way ticket across the country.
-到哪里？ -新墨西哥
- To where? - New Mexico,
果然
of course.
-密码破解了吗？ -还没
- Any luck breaking that code? - Not yet.
-不过这资讯有帮助 -很好
- But this helps, - Good.
-卫勒 -长官？
- Wheeler! - Sir?
所有包含NM的组合
Every combination that has NM in it.
我要你调查 里面是否有符合新墨西哥州的地名
I want you to check it to see if it contains a location in New Mexico.
-现在就办 -现在？
- I want it done now. - Now?
对，立刻办
Yeah, right now.
你跟亚历很熟吗？
So how well do you know Alex?
他熟我的程度超过我熟他
He knows me better than I know him.
他的确是个封闭的人 但是他以前不是这样的
He's a closed book, all right. But he wasn't always like that.
我们结婚前几年
In the first few years of our marriage...
他其实很浪漫
...he was actually romantic.
然后有一天，他忽然K
And then one day, out of nowhere...
-忽然怎么了？ -一切都变了
- out of nowhere, what? - Everything changed.
-他开始想尽办法离开 -离开婚姻？
- He became obsessed with getting out. - Out of the marriage?
他想离婚
Getting out of the marriage.
想把我赶出房子，赶出他的生活
Getting me out of the house, out of his life.
他就这样离开我
He left me.
丢下我们俩
He left the both of us.
你说他让你害怕，为什么？
You said you were scared of him. Why is that?
他开始出现怪异行为
He started acting strange.
无时无刻待在后院做园艺
Started spending all of his time in the backyard gardening, of all things.
他原本有洁癖
I mean, the man was a neat freak.
皮鞋要是刮到，他就会丢掉
He'd throw away a pair of shoes if they even got scuffed.
但是他却在后院 弄得全身肮脏
But he'd be out there, all covered in dirt...
身旁都是肥料和碱水
...and surrounded by these huge bags of fertilizer and lye.
后院才刚铺上草皮 他却挖开草皮K
We just put this new sod in, and he just tore it all up...
做了一个花圃出来
...and planted a flower bed.
有一次我到后院找他
And I went out back once to talk to him.
他却对我大喊
And he screamed at me...
叫我不准靠近花园
...and said not to come near the garden.
说那是他的花园
Said that it was his.
抱歉，你想的话 可以休息一下
I'm sorry. If you... If you wanna take a break.
我只想得到一个解释 他为何忽然放弃婚姻
All I wanted was an explanation why things ended so suddenly.
亚历只回答我K
And all Alex could say was:
“有些事是你无法掌控的”
"Sometimes things happen that are just out of your control."
（联络人，亚历曼宏）
你女儿房间那张照片
So the picture in your daughter's bedroom.
拍摄地点就在旋转木马，对吧？
The exact location where it was taken was a merry-go-round, right?
对
Yeah.
所以你只需要在旋转木马旁等待
All you have to do is wait by the merry-go-round.
班哲明会到那里等你
Right where Benjamin's expecting you.
那有必要吗？
Is that necessary?
-班哲明甚至K -只是以防万一
- I mean, Benjamin's not even... - It's precautionary.
听着，我合作了 你们就别再来烦我和小孩
Look, I do this, you leave me and my child alone.
我向你保证
You have my word.
我妻子来了吗？
Is my wife there?
-她来了 -去带她吧
- Yeah, she's here. - Well, let's go get her,
三号，请确认你已到一号位置
Number three, please confirm you're in position, number one,
15秒后有台黑色吉普车 会停在停车场出口
In 15 seconds a black jeep is gonna pull up by the parking lot entrance.
冲上车
Run to it.
克里斯？
Chris?
快去
Go!
-不行，他们会带走蒂蒂 -不会的
- I can't, they're gonna take Dede. - No, they won't.
那男人在跟她说话？看清楚
Is that guy talking to her? Get a read on him.
-就位 -已经解决了，快去
- Move to positions, - It's taken care of. Go!
快去
Go!
她跑了K
She's running. She's running.
快，出动K
Go, go, go! Move, move!
上车，坐稳了
Get in! Hold on.
是2007年份的黑吉普车 没有车牌
It's a 2007 black Jeep. License plates have been removed.
正前往追赶K不！
We're in pursuit, headed... No!
把卡车开走K
Move the truck.
把卡车开走
我叫你开走
I said move it!
-我女儿在哪里？ -拿去
- Where is my child? - Here.
-蒂蒂？ -是我，宝贝
- Dede? - Hey, it's me, baby.
我只是想告诉你 不会有事的
Hey, look, I just wanna tell you that everything is gonna be okay.
我们一家可以团聚，我保证
We're gonna be a family again, I promise you that.
蒂蒂在哪里？他说她在你那边
Where is Dede? He said that you had her!
不K宝贝，别激动
No, no, no, no, no. Be easy, baby.
冷静下来，崔现在正在学校接她出来
Be easy. Trey is picking her up from school right now.
蒂蒂富兰克林，道森小学 立刻把她从学校带走
Dede Franklin, Dawson Elementary. I want her pulled from school, now.
-出了什么事？ -校方说她在考试
- What the hell is going on, man? - They say she's taking a test, man.
但我觉得是在拖延
But I think they're stalling.
关于奥斯卡席尔斯呢？
What about oscar shales?
奥斯卡席尔斯？为何问起他？
Oscar shales? Why is he important?
他是少数逃出 你前夫手掌心的K
Well, he's just the only fugitive to ever successfully elude...
逃犯之一
...your ex-husband.
亚历一心只想追捕他
Alex was consumed with finding him.
毕竟席尔斯对受害者如此残暴 这能怪他吗？
I mean, after what shales did to all of his victims, who could blame him?
他有一整年只查这个案子
It was all he worked on, all he did for a year.
可是我不认为亚历的怪异举止
But I don't think that it was the stress of chasing shales...
要归咎于追捕席尔斯的庞大压力
...that caused Alex to start behaving erratically.
为什么？
Why is that?
因为亚历在线索消失后才改变
Because Alex changed after the trail went cold.
我记得很清楚，仿佛是昨日
I remember it like it was yesterday.
他走进厨房里 当时我们结婚已经12年
He just walked into the kitchen, after 12 years of marriage...
他说要我立刻离开那幢房子
...and says that he wanted me out of the house immediately.
我永远忘不了那天
I'll never forget the date.
6月15号
It was June 15th.
我想访谈可以结束了
I think I have everything I need.
可是你还没问到人际关系和教育背景
You didn't even ask about social history or education.
-调查一般都会问到 -那部份已经调查完毕
- That's standard in these checks. - That's been handled.
我现在要尽快把报告 交给策略行动小组
I have to get these reports filed with strategic operations, AsAP.
-你是策略行动小组的人？ -调查都由他们负责
- You're with strategic operations? - They handle these checks.
911事件后就不是了 梅瑞克先生
Not since the 9/11 realignment, Mr. Merrick.
现在是由资讯长负责
The chief information officer does them now.
上次调查亚历的就是他们
They handled Alex's last check.
当探员晋升到你丈夫的阶级时
When an agent reaches a level as high as your ex-husband's...
策略行动小组就会再度接手
...s.o. Takes over... again.
都是拜官僚之赐，感谢你的咖啡
Bureaucracies. Thank you for the coffee.
听着，快把她带走
Look, just get her out of there.
他们来了
They're here.
不K
No, no, no, no.
-我们得走了 -别管了
- No, see, we gotta go. - Don't worry about it.
你去发动车子，快去
Just get the car started, all right? Go.
-爸爸 -宝贝
- Daddy! - Hey, baby.
-准备走了吗？ -要去哪里？
- You ready to go? - Where are we going?
-迪士尼乐园 -富兰克林先生，你不能K
- Disneyland. - Mr. Franklin, you can't...
-FBI，站住 -抓住他K
- FBI, stop! - Get him, get him!
快！我们走
Come on, let's go!
我们走，宝贝K
Let's go, baby. Let's go, baby.
开车K
Come on, go, go, go!
富兰克林带走小孩 我重复，富兰克林带走了小孩
Franklin has the child! Repeat, Franklin has the child!
晚安，贺兰德太太
Evening, Mrs, Hollander,
你今晚真是美丽
Don't you look lovely this evening?
你不应该欺骗我 天啊，我竟然让你接近我的孩子
You should've told me what you were. My God, I let you near my children!
别以为我会忘记你家门前的模样
Don't think I won't remember what your front steps look like.
离路边远一点，你想被抓到吗？
Come on now, get away from the road. You wanna get caught?
我看到你在餐厅时 打量那些女孩
I saw you checking out those girls back at the diner.
-什么？ -少来了，从实招来
- What? - Come on, fess up.
我只是想确定 她们没有盯着我们瞧
No, I was making sure they weren't staring at us.
什么，盯着她们的屁股吗？
With what, their asses?
巴拿马有很多美女 她们喜欢美国人
Beautiful girls in Panama. They love Americans.
很好
Cool.
你接触女孩有多久了？
So how long you known about girls?
够久了
Long enough.
从什么时候开始？
Since when?
-13岁 -13岁？
- Thirteen. - Thirteen?
对方是谁？
With who?
-唐娜安萨米 -她是隔壁的小孩
- Donna Anselmi. - She was the kid next door.
-她比你K -比我大四岁吧？
- She was about... - Four years older than me?
你妈请她当你的法文家教
Your mom was paying her for French lessons.
她教得很好
Well, she earned the money.
过来，离路边远一点
Come on. Away from the road.
你还是太近了，过来
You're still way too close. Let's go.
-你想学把戏吗？葛蕾西 -什么把戏？
- You want to learn some tricks, Gracey? - Like what?
我让你进入我的人生
I let you into my life,
18K是27
Eighteen, 27.
晚安，贺兰德太太
Evening, Mrs, Hollander,
你好吗？小泰迪
How you feeling, little Teddy?
NM，6K
NM, six...
NM
NM.
三
Three.
NM
NM.
NM，6-3
NM, 6-3.
NMK
NM, NM, NM...
（希拉）
明天
Tomorrow.
潘，我现在没空和你聊
Pam, I really can't talk right now.
也许我待会儿再打
Maybe I should call back,
-你是谁？ -我想你心知肚明
- Who is this? - I think you already know.
如果你伤害了潘K
If you've done anything to Pam.
-或是我儿子K -你我皆知，你的家人都没事
- Or my boy... - We both know your family's fine,
不过你的离开 让潘很难过
Although Pam did seem a little upset about you leaving,
话说回来，你别无选择不是吗？
But then, you had to, didn't you?
因为你不能让她发现
Because you couldn't let her find out,
-发现什么？ -奥斯卡席尔斯，你还记得吧？
- Find out about what? - Oscar Shales, you remember?
溜出你手掌心的逃犯
The one that got away.
只是他没跑太远，对吧？
Except he didn't get too far, did he?
-你的功力减退了，史柯菲 -也许
- You're slipping, scofield. - Maybe,
咱们试想一会儿
Let's hypothesize for a moment.
假装是我逮捕到席尔斯
Let's pretend I was the one who caught shales.
我想我没办法 把这疯子交给法庭审判
I don't think I could have just handed that psychopath over to the courts,
因为我耗费心思这么久 都抓不到他
Not after he had eluded me for so long,
让我很没面子
Made me look bad.
你在外逃亡太久了，小子
You've been out in the sun way too long, boy.
调查局的薪水不错
You Feds make a nice living,
但还不足以让你挖掉昂贵的草皮
But not so nice you go around tearing up expensive sod,
除非你打算挖洞
Not unless you had to do a little digging.
除非你要藏某样东西
Not unless you wanted to hide something.
或是某人
Or someone,
所以你才用碱水，对吧？
That's what all the lye was for, wasn't it?
因为碱水有两种
See, because there are two kinds of lye,
少量的第一种是园丁的最佳良伴
Small amounts of the first kind can be a gardener's best friend,
大袋的第二种 可用来分解尸体
And large bags of the other kind decomposes bodies.
你真该去写悬疑小说
Oh, you should write mystery novels.
我不知道你是怎么想的
I don't know about you,,,
但如果我把人埋在自家后院
...but if I buried someone in my own back yard...
我会随时想起这件事
,,, I'd think about it all the time,
我会想K 也许我应该把尸体移开
I'd think maybe I should move that body,
但我又想到
Then I'd remember,,,
DNA会渗进土壤里 所以即使尸体不见了
,,, that DNA leaches into soil, so even when the body was gone,,,
我灭尸的证据还是存在
...the proof of what I'd done would still be there.
我可以想像那种感受
I can imagine how it feels,
那种压力
The pressure,
无止境的恐惧
The constant fear.
是一般人是无法承受的
It's more than a man can bear.
我给你一个机会
I'm gonna give you a chance,
放弃追捕 让我和我的家人消失
Back off, let me and my family disappear.
我会以保守你的小秘密回报你
And in return, I'll keep your little secret,
听起来如何？
How does that sound?
像死囚的遗言
Like a dead man talking.
我知道你没料到 事情会演变成这样
I know it's not how you wanted this to play out,
可是有些事是你K
But sometimes things happen that are just...
无法掌控的
,,, out of your control,
这就是个例子
This is one of those times,
你自己保重
Take care of yourself.
我们稍后见了，麦可
I'll see you soon, Michael.
对了，麦可 我们可能会比你想像中更快见到面
Oh, and Michael, it just may be sooner than you think.
午觉睡得愉快吗？
Did you have a nice nap?
梦见翩翩起舞的12岁女孩？
Visions of 12-year-olds dancing in your head?
-你们私闯民宅 -这里没人住，天真小女孩
- You're trespassing. - Nobody lives here anymore, Goldilocks.
屋主似乎连夜搬走
Seems the owner hit the bricks...
就在她听说某人又重获自由时
...as soon as she heard a certain someone had re-entered society.
匆忙地搬走 有些家当甚至没有拿走
Left in a hurry too. Even left some stuff behind.
这里就是西奥多展现他 变态长才的地方
So this is where Theodore practiced "Pervert Knows Best."
这里是他一度 和家人吃晚餐的地方
This is where he had his family supper.
至于这里，我想K
And that, I believe...
就是你与贺兰德太太 表达爱意的地方
...is where you and Mrs. Hollander expressed your love.
告诉我，小泰迪 你会要她穿上童装
Tell me, little Teddy, did you make her wear Dr. Dentons...
手上拿着午餐盒 来让你感到兴奋吗？
...and hold a lunchbox to help you get all worked up?
布拉德，我不指望一个K
Bradley, I couldn't possibly expect...
还和妈妈同住的成年男子
...a grown man who still lives with his mama...
会了解爱情的奥妙
...to understand the machinations of love.
想知道我们如何找到你吗？
You want to know how we found you?
你寄了52封信到这个地址
Fifty-two mash notes sent by you to this address.
内容都是恳求贺兰德太太 和你这可悲的人复合
All of them begging Mrs. Hollander to take your white-trash ass back.
而每一封都被标上 “退回收信人”
And every one of them boomeranged to Fox River...
被退回监狱
...marked "Return To sender."
狱警看信时可真开心 对吧？葛瑞
The guards had a real laugh reading them, didn't we, Geary?
那当然
Oh, damn right, we did.
你这只爪看起来真凄惨，滑头
That is one mangy looking paw you got there, slick.
怎么了？童子军反击了？ 葛瑞
What happened, Boy scout fight back? Geary.
现在你要告诉我K
Now, you're gonna tell me...
威莫兰的钱藏在哪里
...where you stashed Westmoreland's money.
否则我会一针针 把你拆掉
Or I'm gonna pluck you like a chicken, stitch by stitch.
好吧，你们想知道钱在哪里？
Fine, you wanna know where the money is?
我昨晚在床上全部花在你妈妈身上了
I did spend a whole bunch of it last night on your mama.
答错了
Wrong answer.
过来，宝贝
Come on, baby.
你好吗K？
How are you?
没事吧？
You're good?
-没事 -她很好
- Yeah. - She's okay.
-宝贝K -什么事？
- Baby. - Yeah?
我们该怎么办？
What do we do now?
我们不用等太久
We didn't have to wait too long at all.
我们该怎么做？
What are we gonna do?
想办法上火车，走吧
Get a ticket on the train. Come on.
在这里等火车来
Just wait here until the train comes.
（离希拉73里）
对，我想就是他们两个
Yeah, I think that's the guy right over there.
两名白人男子徒步 从威考克车站逃逸
Two Caucasian males on foot, fleeing the Willcox station.
我在跑了
I'm running.
罗杰！
L. J!
-罗杰 -不准动
- L. J! - Hold it, right there.
-站住 -不准动
- Stop. - Don't move.
拜托K
Please, please.
-不关他的事 -趴下
- He's got nothing to do with this. - Face down!
-拜托 -快点
- Please. - Now!
上手铐
Cuff them.
罗杰，对不起
L.J., I'm sorry.
嫌犯已制服，疑似林克柏劳
Suspect in custody. Possible ID, Lincoln Burrows.
对不起，罗杰，对不起
I'm sorry. L.J., I'm sorry.